<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bex Edmondson</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>http://www.bexedmondson.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.bexedmondson.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 18:17:34 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 18:17:34 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting this blog off in spectacular fashion, here’s my wrap-up of my day at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.egx.net/egx&quot;&gt;EGX&lt;/a&gt;! I travelled up all the way from Exeter to Birmingham, and it was definitely worth the six different trains I had to take (!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/egx2015/traincollage.png&quot; alt=&quot;I should probably start a train photography business…&quot; title=&quot;I should probably start a train photography business…&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, what an atmosphere. It was so great to be around thousands of people who loved games as much as me, and the buzz was palpable. While there was an (understandably) enormous amount of hype around the big budget studio releases like Call of Duty: Black Ops 3 and Assassin’s Creed: Syndicate, people seemed just as willing to try out all the indie games in the EGX Rezzed Zone and the Leftfield Collection. I didn’t see quite as much cosplay as at London ComicCon in August, but EGX was host to the UK Preliminaries for the European Cosplay Gathering so I saw a fair bit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/egx2015/jokercrowd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Not pictured: four separate Lara Crofts that had just passed.&quot; title=&quot;Not pictured: four separate Lara Crofts that had just passed.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;careers-bar&quot;&gt;Careers Bar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I went in the first place, however, was the Careers Bar, run by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gamesindustry.biz/&quot;&gt;GamesIndustry.biz&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://ukie.org.uk/&quot;&gt;Ukie&lt;/a&gt;. I started off my day speaking to Creative Assembly, who were very welcoming and gave me some good advice I hadn’t heard before: namely, to create more technical C++ programmes alongside the full games I’m working on. I’m hoping that working on my final year project will give me a few opportunities to do that, and I’ve got one boids simulation ready to start. I had a chat with the guys at the Microsoft Studios stand as well, and they were very friendly and gave me a free lollipop. I mean, that might normally be a tactic to curry favour with six year olds, but it worked on me…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the careers section wasn’t huge, unfortunately, and mostly consisted of game development schools. I did try one student project, but I broke it in the first thirty seconds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/egx2015/trscreens.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The queue for RotTR was so long I finished an entire book and still had time to take photos of the trailer.&quot; title=&quot;The queue for RotTR was so long I finished an entire book and still had time to take photos of the trailer.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tomb-raider&quot;&gt;Tomb Raider&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I must be honest here and say that I did spend a large proportion of the day queuing to indulge my inner fangirl – I spent nearly two hours waiting to play the sequel to my all-time favourite game, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.xbox.com/en-GB/games/rise-of-the-tomb-raider&quot;&gt;Rise of the Tomb Raider&lt;/a&gt;. And oh, was it worth it. The preview started with an explosive cutscene (literally) and I immediately noticed the improvement in graphics. Lara’s new character model thankfully doesn’t look as different to the last one as the promo pictures showed, and struck a nice balance between making her more expressive and keeping her recognisable. I loved the reintroduction of the swan dive from the older Crystal Dynamics Tomb Raider games! And I’ve got to hand it to them, Lara squeezing out her ponytail after she’d clambered out of the water was a really nice touch. I won’t say much more so as not to spoil anything, only that I &lt;em&gt;wish&lt;/em&gt; I owned an Xbox One, solely because I want to get it as soon as it’s out – I’ll unfortunately have to wait until the PC release in early 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/egx2015/trcard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The card I got for completing the preview. I have no idea what this is for, but it seems to be part of a set?&quot; title=&quot;The card I got for completing the preview. I have no idea what this is for, but it seems to be part of a set?&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;egx-rezzed&quot;&gt;EGX Rezzed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I headed out of the Tomb Raider preview over to EGX Rezzed, and got to try out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oculus.com/en-us/&quot;&gt;Oculus&lt;/a&gt; for the first time! I was a bit wary of the hype, but it really lived up to expectations. The game on display was &lt;a href=&quot;http://mintgames.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Mint Games’&lt;/a&gt; VRTIGO, a rollercoaster simulator which was the most disorienting thing I’ve ever experienced, but SO much fun! The app that let you create coasters was a great idea, and if I ever get an Oculus of my own this game will be top of the list. To top off the whole experience, the guy at the stand was lovely, and when I commented on the lack of character model he told me it was because he only had a white man and wanted more diversity, which is such a rare and nice thing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/blog/egx2015/oculus.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;This guy was the one before me – he spent the whole time gripping onto the desk to orient himself.&quot; title=&quot;This guy was the one before me – he spent the whole time gripping onto the desk to orient himself.&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the subject of diversity, I played the second instalment of Knee Deep by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.prologuegames.com/&quot;&gt;Prologue Games&lt;/a&gt;, a visual murder mystery novel. I was intrigued by the plot and I really liked the way they displayed the game as a piece of theatre, and the developers were really friendly. However, I was very definitely not impressed by the fact that the sole playable female character had the option to do a “silly response” for every dialogue option, which was only put in to let the player make her into the ditsy “lol i’m so rand0m!!1!” stereotype. After talking to the devs about this, they seemed to be quite proud of this, but I fail to see why a developer would be happy about giving their players an option to reduce a woman to a bland stereotype. The team was very nice overall though, and this was really the only bad point about the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other visual novel I played was &lt;a href=&quot;http://heraldgame.com/&quot;&gt;Herald&lt;/a&gt; by Wispfire. I talked to a developer and the narrative designer, who were both fantastic! I’m helping develop my own visual novel at the moment, and our conversation definitely influenced some changes I’m going to put into it. The story centres around a young guy of mixed heritage who’s looking for his origins. The initial part of the story that I played already gave me a feel of the power the player had over the story, and it’ll be on my to-buy list as soon as it’s released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t get to talk to many other developers, but as I was wandering around the indie games section I saw a couple that grabbed my attention: Megaton Rainfall, Twin Souls and Iron Fish. &lt;a href=&quot;http://megatonrainfall.com/&quot;&gt;Megaton Rainfall&lt;/a&gt; has you playing as a superhero that destroys cities, as far as I can work out, and looks like it’ll be a lot of fun. &lt;a href=&quot;http://twinsoulsgame.com/&quot;&gt;Twin Souls: The Path of Shadows&lt;/a&gt;, by Lince Works, looks like a 3D version of Mark of the Ninja, and had some brilliant teleportation mechanisms and animations, reminiscent of Dishonored. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ironfishgame.com/&quot;&gt;Iron Fish&lt;/a&gt;, a psychological deep-sea thriller, had a pretty big team around it, but I didn’t try it out because I am very very bad at swimming in games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://speelbaars.com/?page_id=136&quot;&gt;Lumini&lt;/a&gt;, though, deserves its own paragraph. It looked like a mix of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.oriblindforest.com/&quot;&gt;Ori and the Blind Forest&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://thatgamecompany.com/games/flower/&quot;&gt;Flower&lt;/a&gt;, with a bit of the Pikmin mechanic mixed in as well, and it was really beautiful. I watched a young kid play it, and it seemed like the controls were natural and easy to use. It was the only game on the Rising Star Games stand that had been fully released, and I’ve put it straight on my Steam wishlist. I was a little less impressed by its neighbouring game, Lumo: I was intrigued until the promoter started talking to me about it, and described it as the renaissance of 1980s isometric games. I’m afraid I have no time for games that are created solely to indulge the nostalgia of thirty-year-old men - sorry (not sorry)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;one-last-thing&quot;&gt;One last thing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A final quick shoutout to &lt;a href=&quot;http://retr8bit.com/&quot;&gt;Retr8bit&lt;/a&gt; – I met one of their people on the train, and she was lovely. I’m planning on buying one of their adorable 8-bit inspired Hama bead characters as soon as I can afford one (they’re really not expensive, I’m just a very broke student at the moment).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, EGX 2015 was unmissable. If I can, I’ll be headed up to EGX Rezzed in April next year, and I’ll go back to EGX for more than one day next year! Thanks so much to the organisers and the hosts at the NEC Birmingham.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll see you guys soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 22:04:10 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.bexedmondson.com/blog/2015/09/28/egx-2015.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bexedmondson.com/blog/2015/09/28/egx-2015.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Carmilla Game</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Set in the gap between seasons 1 and 2 of the Carmilla webseries, The Carmilla Game is an unofficial visual novel that lets players experience the adventures of the main characters in the Styrian wilderness. From bears to riddles to just a little bit of heartbreak, players get to make decisions and watch as the consequences unfold. The game is currently in development, and will be free to play on Windows, Mac OSX, and Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.bexedmondson.com/games/2015/09/22/the-carmilla-game.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.bexedmondson.com/games/2015/09/22/the-carmilla-game.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>games</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
